Major Typhoon #13 has reached Northern Japan after moving along the coast.
大型の台風十三号は本州を太平洋図に北上
現在関東上空を通過中です
Kanba - 9 years ago - Takakura house, living room - *A stormy night. Himari is really sick with a fever. We called the hospital, but they coldly brushed us off.
Storm Warning
West Tokyo
Nakano Ward
Suginami Ward
Gunma Ward
Typhoon #13
06:00 Today
18:00 Today
06:00 Tomorrow
18:00 Tomorrow
It is currently passing through Kanto area.
All the ambulances have already been dispatched?
救急車が全部出払ってる
But we need one too...
でもうちだって娘の熱が下がらないんです　このままじゃ…
My daughter's fever isn't going down.
At this rate...
Honey?
あなた…
Give it up.
もういい
Kanba
Shoma
Himari
Kenzan
Chiemi
Takakura
Okay, I'll get going.
じゃ　行ってくる　家のこと頼んだぞ
Take care of things at home.
Me too!
僕も
No, don't.
だめよ
Kanba, come back!
冠葉　戻って
Dad!
父さん
That idiot.
あの馬鹿
I'm going too!
俺も一緒に行く
Kanba!
冠葉
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
駅のホーム
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
響くファンファーレ
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
御免ね
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
運命が笑う
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
臨界点突破してる
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
限界なら既に去って
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
絶対的支配だって
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
崩壊
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
叫ぶよ
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
僕は目を閉じるよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter 翻译：英英 校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：笑眯眯
gg subs modified with Honorifics and Eastern name ordered
Corrected a few lines timing wise
Rock over Japan insert song added in with corrected opening and ending typesetting
To'oh General Hospital
Her physical exam indicates that her recovery is stable and she seems to be doing fine.
検査結果も安定しているし　状態もいいようだ
もう暫くこのまま様子を見てみよう
Let's take a wait-and-see approach for a while longer.
Excellent, thank you.
そうですか　ありがとうございます
I have to say, this is quite strange.
こんな言い方をしてはなんだが　実に不思議だよ
In this line of work, we encounter cases we're forced to call "miracles" once in a blue moon
こういう仕事をしていると
まるに奇跡としか言い様のない症例に遭遇するが
Your sister's is one of them.
妹さんの場合は正にそうだ
Actually... I wanted to talk to you about that.
実は　そのことで　先生にお話が
うん　何がな
What is it?
Can you take a look at this?
これを検査してもらえませんか
もしかするとこれがひまりの奇跡の原因かもしれないんです
This may be the cause of Himari's miracle.
This is just a theory of mine, but...
これはあくまで僕の推測ですが
maybe this hat is actually...
この帽子の正体は
an extraterrestrial organism.
多分宇宙生命体です
This extraterrestrial organism is using some sort of power to cure Himari's-
この宇宙生命体が何等かのパワーでひまりの病気を
なるほど　それも一理あるな
I see, that's a good idea.
I'm right?
やっばり
You're a pretty funny guy.
君はなかなか面白い子だね
Yes, funny.
そう　面白い
That's a great thing.
それはとても良いことだ
Right...
Laughter, it's laughter!
笑いだよ　笑い
笑いは免疫力を強化する
Laughter strengthens your immune system.
The effect has been garnering attention in the medical community lately.
今医療の分野でもその効果が注目されていてね
その帽子は宇宙から来た何　生命体
That hat came from the space?
An organism?
はははは
Keep making your sister laugh like that!
その調子で妹さんも毎日笑わせてあげることだ
Oh my, we have to crush him soon.
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
You must be terribly worried about your job right now.
心配でしょう　お仕事のこと考えていらしたんじゃないの
Oh... yeah, I am.
ああ　はい
It's my fault.
わたくしのせいね　阿佐美さんに無理なお願いをしてしまったから
This all happened because I asked too much of you.
No, it's not your fault Natsume-san...
いいえ　そんな　夏芽さんのせいなんかじゃない…
You poor thing.
可哀相に
I can't forgive whoever did this to you.
事故のこと　本当に許せないは
But, is it true you don't remember anything, save someone pushing you?
でも　誰かに押されたこと以外　何も覚えてらっしゃらないですって
実はあんまりよく覚えていないんです　あの時の事
I don't really remember what happened.
But...
でも　でも
But... I thought I saw someone right before the accident.
事故の前に誰かを見た気が
I remember it now!
思い出した　私見たんです
I saw!
I saw him...
あの時彼が
You witnessed him?
あなた　それをご覧になったの
Y-Yes.
もう結構
I've heard enough.
夏芽さん
Natsume-san?
Update on Kuho Asami, who fell down a subway escalator a few days ago.
先日地下鉄構内のエスカレーターで事故に合われた
久宝阿佐美さんの続報です
最新の情報によりますと
According to the latest report,
久宝さんは事故前後の事情について
何も記憶していないと警察に返答しているとことです
Kuho-san has told the police she doesn't remember anything before or after the incident.
The police is continuing their investigation by searching for witnesses.
警察は更に目撃者などの情報を集めて捜査を進めています
Ikebe Sweets
Elephant's
Egg Manjū
Hello, it's Hibari...
こんにちは　ひまりです
ね　今日はどうしたの　おじさん
So, what brings you here today, Uncle?
実はな　冠葉
Sorry to bring this up all of a sudden, but...
急な話で申し訳ないだが
Well, it's not like this house will sell immediately.
いや　何　この家を売ると言っても
すぐに動向でわけじゃないんだ
もちろんお前たちの事はおじさん責任いう持って何とかする
Of course, I'll make sure you're all taken care of.
I'll talk with the relatives you will be staying with.
預かり先の親戚にもちゃんと話はつける
Although, I don't think the three of you will be able to stay together.
三人一緒は無理かもしれないが
What about Himari?
ひまりは
She's sick.
あいつは病気なんだぞ
そりゃ
Well...
Sorry, I forgot to make you tea.
悪い　お茶入れてなかったな
I'll take care of Himari.
ひまりはうちできちんと面倒を見るから
何があれば　すぐに知らせるさ
You'll be the first to know if something happens.
I hate to say this, but...
言いたかないけど　冠葉
Kanba, your parents aren't going to come home.
お前たちの両親もうここには戻ってこないよ
I'll come up with the money.
金は俺が工面する
What?
How much money do I need to keep this house?
いくら用意すればこの家を売らずに済む
冠葉　何も　私は
Kanba, I'm not...
I mean, how are you going to make that kind of money anyway?
第一お前がどこできる金額じゃ
How much?!
いくらなんだよ
I have a date with Papa today.
今日はパパとデートだ
I'm not a child anymore, so it's a bit embarrassing.
もう子供じゃないのに　ちょっと恥ずかしい
By the way, I haven't told Papa about him yet.
ちなみに　パパにはまだ彼の事言ってない
Because he'll get jealous!
だってやきもちをやいちゃうから
I want to remain as Papa's precious treasure, for now.
いまのところ私まだパパの大切な宝ものでいたいんのだ
Two Seafood Curry Lunchs.
シーフードのカレーランチ二つ
That's fine with you, right, Papa?
パパもそれでいいよね
Yeah.
ああ
Oh, Special Antarctica Parfait.
南極スペシャルパフェ-　ペンギンのフィギュアつきだって
It comes with a penguin figure!
How cute.
可愛い
じゃ　それも一つ
Then, we'll have one of those, too.
Certainly.
かしこまりました
懐かしいな
It sure brings back memories.
ね　今度またあの水族館行こうよ
Let's go to that aquarium again next time.
That aquarium?
あの水族館
そう　ママと三人でよく行ったあの池袋の水族館
Yes, the one we used to go all the time with Mama.
That aquarium in Ikebukuro.
Remember when you tried to get a closer look at the penguin parade,
パパペンギンの行進が面白いって通路に乗り出したら
係の人に物凄く怒ったじゃない
and a zookeeper yelled at you?
Did that happen?
そうだったっけ
そうだよ　三人でお揃いねって
ペンギンの携帯ストラップも買ったでしょう
Yeah, it did!
The three of us bought matching phone straps too.
Oh, right, we did.
そうだったな　リンゴはペンギン好きだったもんな
You really love penguins.
You said this strap was like made for m-
パパが　リンゴお前のために作られたみたい
Sorry, give me a minute.
あ　ちょっと御免
Hello, yes.
もしもし　ああ　今娘と一緒なんだ
I'm with my daughter right now.
It's my visitation day.
例の面会日です
Right, I'm eating dinner with you.
夜は君と食べるから
Why don't you bring Aoi-chan?
よかったら　娘さん青いちゃんも一緒にどうかな
三人でお揃いの携帯ストラップ
The matching phone strap for the three of us.
Did you know, Papa?
ねえ　パパ
この前のカレーの日
私が一人で作たカレーを多蕗さんに食べてもらたんだよ
Tabuki-san ate the curry I made all by myself last Curry Day.
Yes, Ringo.
そうよ　リンゴ
今日のミッションはまだ終わったわけじゃない
Your mission for today is not over yet.
だって　これから多蕗さんに
Because Tabuki-san is going to...
French Cuisine
Best Mont Blanc
in the World
ありがとうございました　merci
Thank you very much.
Merci.
Visiting Tabuki-san on the way home with a Mont Blanc.
帰り道お土産のモンブランを持って多蕗君を訪ねる
Tabuki-san loves Mont Blancs.
多蕗君はモンブランが大好き
It'll make him fall madly in love with me if I bring him one.
それを持って来たあたしにもきっと夢中にならざるを得ないはずだ
うんー　美味い
It's so good!
やっばりここのが僕のベストザモントモンブランだな
This place makes my personal "best of Mont Blanc" list!
Tabuki-kun, you're so fabulous max!
多蕗君たら　Fabulous Max
この味　もう夢中になれざるをえない
This taste!
It's making me fall madly in love!
どうしたの
What's the matter?
いいや　誰かに見られていたような
Uh... I felt like we were being watched.
You must be imagining things.
気のせいじゃない
Ringo-chan?
リンゴちゃん
What's wrong?
どうしたの
D-Dad...
父さん
悪い　御免　御免なさい
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
All right, let's go.
よし　行くぞ
As promised.
確かに
Kan-chan sure is late.
冠ちゃん遅いね
Sheesh, what's he doing without even contacting us?
たっく　連絡もせずに何してんのか
I bet he's with a girl right now, as usual!
どうせいつもの女絡みだろうけど
Ugh!
嫌だ　嫌だ
"I don't want to be infected by yucky playboy Kanba-germs!"
女だらしの冠葉菌が移るでしょ
Right?
Yeah, our dinner's getting cold!
そうそう　せっかくの御飯が冷めるだけだ
Let's just eat without him.
いいよ　先に食べちゃよう
Oginome-san, I'm sure you don't want to get home too late.
荻野目さんだって帰りが遅くなると困るだろうし
It's okay, my mom always come home late from working overtime...
それは
大丈夫　お母さんいつも残業で遅いし
No!
いいや
There's no need to wait for that idiot brother of ours!
あのバカ兄貴を待てやる必要なんかない
Let's eat!
頂きます
Sho-chan, how's the beef and potato stew?
晶ちゃん　この肉ジャガ如何
Oh, is this...
これで
Yup, I seasoned it with curry!
そう　カレー入り肉ジャガ
リンゴちゃんのレシピなの
It's Ringo-chan's recipe.
Wow, it's surprisingly good.
意外といけるな
"Curry should be eaten with people you love," right?
カレーは大切な人と一緒に　だもんね
Yes, curry should be eaten with people you love.
そう　カレーは大切な人と一緒によ
We don't put peas in the stew.
うちはグリーンピース入れないんだ
Oh, really?
そうなんだ
Yeah...
そうだ　今話さないでどうする
I have to talk about it now.
Um, Oginome-san.
あの　荻野目さん
I have a favor to ask of you.
君に折り入って頼みたいことがあるんだけど
What is it?
何
You had a notebook on you when we went birdwatching, right?
この間のバードウォッチングの時　君ノート持てたよね
Can you let me borrow that notebook?
よかったら　あのノート貸してもらえないかな
Just for a while.
ほんのちょっとの間でいいんだ
I'll return it to you when I'm done with it.
用が済んだらすぐに返すから
So...
だから
Don't be ridiculous.
馬鹿言わないで
Why do I have to let you borrow it?
どうしてあれは貴方に貸さなきゃいけないの
Well...
それは
No, absolutely not.
だめ　絶対貸さない
It's not something I can lend to others.
第一あれは人に貸していいよのものじゃない
なんで
Why not?
あんなのただのスケジュール帳だろう
Isn't it just an agenda?
You saw?
見たのね　ひどい
How could you?!
偶然にちらっとだけだよ
I just happened to glance at it.
But they were just random plans... more like your ambition!
でもあれはただの予定っていうか
君の勝手な願望じゃないか
No!
違う
It's... it's my fate.
あれは　あれは運命なんだから
My future is written in that notebook.
あのノートには私の未来が書いてある
It's my Fate Diary.
私の運命日記なのよ
Fate Diary? That's...
運命日記って　そんな
I told you the truth.
さあ　私は正直に話したわ
次は貴方の番
It's your turn.
How did you know about it?
どうしてあれの事知ってるの　どうしてあれが必要なの　説明して
Why do you need it?
Explain yourself.
Fine.
分かった　話すよ
I'll tell you.
What's this?
何
Oh, the souvenir from the aquarium?
あ　この間の水族館のお土産
Don't be shocked when I tell you, it's actually...
驚かないで　聞いてくれ
this hat's is actually...
実はこの帽子の正体は 宇宙生命体なんだ
an extraterrestrial organism.
This extraterrestrial organism wants your notebook.
この宇宙生命体が君のノート
いいや　日記を持って来いって命令するんだよ
It's ordering us to get your diary.
もし命令を破ったら
If we disobey...
ふざけないで　ふざけないでよ
Stop screwing with me.
Stop screwing with me!
馬鹿にして　こちは真面目に聞いてるのに
I'm not stupid!
I was being serious.
I'm not lying!
嘘じゃないよ
君だって運命日記とかなんとか意味不明だろう
You were blabbering about nonsense like your "Fate Diary" too!
ああ　宇宙生命体って何　頭どうかしちゃってんじゃないの
Huh? What about your "extraterrestrial organism"?
Do you have a screw loose or something?
Survival Strategy!
生存戦略
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Night
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Fight
I'm just a Rock'n Roll Man
I'm just a Rock'n Roll MAN
We're just a Rock'n Roll BAND
We've been running down this road
俺たちは道なりに　歩き続けてきた
標識だらけの道を飛ばし続けていく
Racing through a path full of signs
幾つもの町を抜け　歌い続けてきた
We crossed countless towns, spreading our song
腑抜け野郎共を煽り続けていく
Continuing to torment these cowardly fools
The wind blows even after the lengthy winter
長い長い冬が溶けても風が吹く
今も今も激しく風が吹く
Still storming down the road
Imagine
Imagine!
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
きっと何物にもなれないお前たちに告げる
What, what, what?!
あれ　あれ　あれれれ
I've had enough of listening to your bullshit, you stupid bitch.
黙って聞いてりゃ
高が雌豚の分際で　勝手放題抜かしやがって
何言ってるの　ひまりちゃん
What are you saying, Himari-chan?
Hurry and hand over your rotten delusional ambition, this "Fate Diary," to that dumbass.
いいから　さっさとてめの腐った妄想の垂れ流し
もとい　運命日記とやらそこの小僧に渡しやがれ
H-Hey, what the hell is going on?
ち　ちょっと　なんなのよこれは
ひまりちゃん　一体全体どうしちゃったの
Himari-chan, what's wrong with you?
What's wrong with you?
どうかしてるの貴様の方だ
You perverted stalker slut.
このストーカーのぶ変態女
Why would you say something so mean, Himari-chan...
ひまりちゃん　何でそんなひどいことを
This is all a big joke, right?
全部冗談だよね
ペー　わらわに口答えするとは汚らわしい
Such insolence! How dare you talk back to me?
この脳みそド腐れゲロ豚ビッチ娘が
You rotten puke-brained bitch-ass whore.
That was totally uncalled for!
ひ　ひどい
You didn't have to call me that!
そこまでいうことはないじゃないいい
Hey, slave.
おら　下僕
お前もぼさっとしてないで　ちゃっちゃと日記を奪ちまうだよ
Don't just stand there! Go snatch her diary.
ええ　そんなこと言ったて
How am I supposed to do that?
I can't snatch it from her if you drop her down the...
落としちゃったら奪い様がないじゃ　か
hole...
ば　ば　馬鹿にして
Don't underestimate me!
Begone!
こんなもの
What have you done?
なんてことするんだ
あれはひまりの
That's Himari's...
Wait for me, truck!
そこのトラック待って
何よ　高が帽子で大げさな
It's just a dumb hat. What's his problem?
Himari-chan?
ひまりちゃん
Come on, stop!
待ってってば
Shoma?
晶馬
Aniki!
兄貴　そのトラック
That truck!
What?!
なんでだよ
Damn, what a rotten day!
くそ　なんて一日だ
Yes! Please stop!
閉めた　止まってってくれよ
Damn it!
くそ
よし　もうチョイ
Yes, just a little farther...
親父の靴を穿いてみた
俺にはちょっとキツイけど
She's safe now.
これでもう安心だな
Kanba, you've done well too.
冠葉お前も頑張ったな（なかなか渋い音を出す）
stepping slipping it's my daddy's shoes
通り過ぎない嵐なんか何処にもない(トンガリ靴を穿いたまま）
No storm lasts forever.
But you can't protect the people you love if you just wait for it to pass.
でも通り過ぎるのを待っていたら　大切な人は守れない
（奴と町を歩いたら）
Never forget that, Kanba.
それを忘れるなよ冠葉（恥ずかしいそうに笑いだす）
Himari! Wake up, Himari!
ひまり（stepping slipping it's my daddy's shoes)
しっかりして　ひまり　（そうさ　これが俺の）
Open your eyes.
目を開けて
Himari...
ひまり　死なないで（俺らの　親父の靴さ）
Don't die.
How could this happen?
そんな　だってただの帽子だと
I thought it was just a hat...
She was just messing around...
ひまりちゃんがふざけて（擦り切れてで傷だらけの古ぼけた靴）
Himari...
ひまり
兄貴　（親父の靴が光出し）
Aniki!
今じゃ一番お気に入り
ビルの谷間で踊り出す
stepping slipping it's my daddy's shoes
Himari!
ひまり
Himari-chan!
ひまりちゃん　（stepping slipping it's my daddy's shoes）
Huh? What happened?
あれ　私
I'm so glad!
よかった
肉ジャガは
What happened to the stew?
Hi, Uncle?
ああ　おじさん
I deposited the money in the store's account.
この間の金　店の口座に振り込んといたから
The money's clean, don't worry.
大丈夫
変な金じゃないから　心配いらないよ
So, Uncle... we can stay in this house for a while longer, right?
それより　おじさん
これで俺たち当分この家に居ていいんだろう
This is What Drives Me
全てが欲しい
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
繋がれたいたら
僕らはどうして
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
もがくのだろう
それは君じゃない
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
君のせいじゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
だからそうじゃない
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
夢のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
上手く伝えきれないけど
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
Dear my future
Dear your future
I know what fate is.
私知ってるよ　運命か何かって
That's why I'll never hesitate.
だから　私に迷いなんかないんだ
I'll be with you forever.
ずっと傍にいるからね
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy in progress.
生存戦略　進行中